Guide to the Village Green Preservation Society Records TEST.999
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Village Green Preservation Society Records
Bulk, 1966-1968
circa 1964-1996
TEST.999
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
3.75 linear feet in 2 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, 1 photograph box, and 1 oversize flat box
The Village Green Preservation Society was a English organization formed in the 1960s devoted to preserving traditional aspects of English country life in the face of industrialization and modernization. The group campaigned in opposition to the rapid acceleration of technology in the name of progress, alleging that it alienated individuals from culture and society; rather, the group advocated for the preservation of sentimental objects or traditions. Materials in this collection include photographs, correspondence with similar organizations, and subject files concerning individual people, places, or things the society campaigned against or advocated for.
Davies, Ray, 1944-
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
History of Village Green Preservation Society
The Village Green Preservation Society was a English organization formed in the 1960s devoted to preserving traditional aspects of English country life in the face of industrialization and modernization. The society was inherently nostalgic in its point of view, with extended campaigns concerning the nature of memories and lapsed friendships. The group campaigned in opposition to the rapid acceleration of technology in the name of progress, alleging that it alienated individuals from culture and society; rather, the group advocated for the preservation of sentimental objects or traditions. In addition to these concrete campaigns, the group also indulged in frequent episodes of pure whimsy, as displayed by their fixation on the so-called "Phenomenal Cat." The society's unofficial motto, which often appeared on their publications, was, "Preserving the old ways from being abused. Protecting the new ways for me and for you."
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Johnny Thunder, 2000.
Scope and Content Note
This collections contains materials documenting the activities and functions of the Village Green Preservation Society. Materials include photographs of social events, correspondence with similar organizations that the society frequently collaborated with, and subject files concerning individual people, places, or things the society campaigned against or advocated for.
Arrangement
Materials are organized into three series, all of which are organized alphabetically.
Series I. Photographs
Series II. Related Organizations
Series III. Subject Files.
Biography of Ray Davies
Ray Davies is cool.
England |x Social conditions |y 20th century.; England |x Social life and customs |y 20th century.
- Series I. Photographs
  Scope and Content Note
  People take pictues of each other just to prove that they really existed.
  - Picture Book, 1962 (Box 1, Cd 1, Box 8)
  - Pictures of Your Momma Taken By Your Papa, A long time ago (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scooby Dooby Doo, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series II. Related Organizations
  - Custard Pie Appreciation Consortium, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Desperate Dan Appreciation Society, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Draught Beer Preservation Society, circa 1970-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Office Block Persecution Affinity, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sherlock Holmes English Speaking Vernacular, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Skyscraper Condemnation Affiliate, 1982 (Flat-file 6, Drawer 2)
- Series III. Subject Files
  - China Cups, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Donald Duck, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dracula, circa 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fu Manchu, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Moriarty, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Strawberry Jam, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Variety, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vaudeville, 1968-1975 (Box 5)
- Series IV. Audio Recordings
  - "Death of a Clown" (Box 13, Box 12, Box 8, Box 102)
  - "Shangri-La" (Box 12, Box 1)
  - "Victoria" (Box 1, Box 8)
  - Retrospective Oral History Interview, 1978
    - Retrospective Oral History Interview: Audio Recording, 1978 (Box 14, Box 16)
    - Retrospective Oral History Interview: Transcript, 1978 (Box 16)